vlex.com 2019-06-01

# Privacy Policy - vLex

## **With vLex you can have peace of mind that…**

Your personal information is **protected**

You maintain **control** of your personal details

You **can** **delete** your personal data whenever you like

### **I. PROCESSING OF PERSONAL DATA OF USERS AND CUSTOMERS**

Up to date with RGPD. 05/25/2018

To provide you with our services, VLEX needs to collect certain information about you. In this Privacy Policy we describe what information is collected, what treatment you receive and how you can manage and control the use of this information.  
By using or interacting with the Service, you enter a binding contract with VLEX and accept the use of your information as explained in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with these terms, please do not use the Service.  
References to Customers, Users, VLEX, Service, Account Administrator, License, Purchase Order, Online Registration, Website or Terms and Conditions should be understood as defined in the Terms and Conditions of Use.

### **1\. WHAT TYPE OF INFORMATION DOES VLEX COLLECT AND USE?**

VLEX may collect and use information about you, which includes, but is not limited to, information of the following types:  
(a) Identifying information (for example, name, user name, address, zip code, telephone number, mobile phone number, email address, identification documents,  the organization in which you work and your position in it).  
(b) Profile information (for example, age, sex, country of residence, language preference, areas of legal specialty and any information you decide to put on your VLEX user profile)  
(c) Electronic identification information (for example, IP addresses, cookies).  
(d) Bank and payment information (for example, credit card information, account number).  
(e) Quality of the search and survey results.  
(f) Information about interactions and your use of the VLEX Services, our products and websites, including connection, platform, device and device information; information on customer performance, error reports, device capacity; bandwidth; statistics about page views; traffic to or from our websites; usage statistics.  
(g) Products or services contracted  
(h) Correspondence between VLEX and you.  
(i) Information on the searches performed and the documents you have accessed. Information on your interactions with documents (for example, bookmark, print, add notes, select fragments)  
(j) Number of users in your Organization  
(h) Recordings of telephone calls with Commercial Agents and / or Customer Service 

### **2\. HOW DOES VLEX USE SUCH INFORMATION AND TO WHAT END?**

Our main objective when gathering information is to provide the user with a safe, efficient, personalized and smooth experience. VLEX collects and uses personal information related to you, or delegates third-party service providers the task of collecting and using such data on behalf of VLEX, as permitted or necessary to:

  * change and customize the functionality and features of the VLEX Services
  * take, process or deliver Purchase Orders made through our websites; send you invoices or notify you of the status of your order
  * provide other services (as indicated at the time of collecting the information)
  * provide customer service and problem solving;
  * Compare information to verify its accuracy
  * inform you about errors and service updates
  * request your opinion or participation in electronic surveys
  * resolve disputes
  * verify your identity
  * customize, evaluate and improve the Services of VLEX and its Contents
  * improve our search feature and the results ranking algorithm
  * organize and carry out offers, promotions, or marketing of VLEX, its affiliates or companies with which it holds a commercial agreement
  * protect your interests and those of VLEX, which specifically includes compliance with the General Terms and Conditions of VLEX, fighting against abusive use and avoiding it (collectively, the Objectives)

### **3\. OUR DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Except as specified below, VLEX will not sell, rent, market or transfer any personal or traffic information or the content of communications outside of VLEX and its affiliates and subsidiaries controlled by it without your explicit permission, unless it has the obligation to do so in accordance with the law or as established by competent authorities.  
VLEX may disclose personal information to respond to legal demands, protect our legal rights or defend against lawsuits, protect VLEX interests, fight against fraud and demand compliance with VLEX policies or protect the rights, property or safety of any person.  
In order to provide the user with the VLEX products that they have requested, VLEX may, in some cases and if necessary, share their personal information with subsidiary and affiliated companies and / or with service providers that are VLEX partners. In all cases, VLEX will require these third parties to take the necessary organizational and technical measures required to protect their personal and traffic information and respect the corresponding legislation. Examples of companies with which VLEX may share your personal information are:

  * Distributors of the VLEX Services
  * Billing companies (automatic billing platforms)
  * Payment processors
  * Auditors, such as KPMG
  * Companies that subcontract the
  * Customer Service or Call
  * Emission and Reception
  * Credit reference or anti-fraud agencies and Insolvency Files
  * Banking entities and financial services companies
  * Marketing and Public Relations Companies, including email sending companies and Analytical Services companies
  * Datacenters and Hosting Companies, such as Amazon Web Services, LLC (USA)
  * Online Software Providers, such as SARL (Switzerland), Salesforce.com, Inc (USA), Netsuite, Inc (USA), Zuora, Inc (USA), Mixpanel, Inc. (USA) or Kissmetrics, Inc. (USA)
  * Collection Companies
  * Online Advertising Companies, such as Google, Inc. (USA)

In some cases, we may communicate your data to other companies of the VLEX group such as Lexdir Global, SL (Spain), so that they can offer you their products and services, for which we explicitly request your consent.

Some VLEX Services may be co-branded and offered together or with associated companies. If you use or subscribe to such Services, you are informed and agree that VLEX and the associated company use the personal information collected in connection with the co-branded product. VLEX offers its products in connection with other websites or services, or can associate with other Internet services to offer a combination of products and services, or additional benefits and services. To determine if the combined option may be useful, once you have given your consent, VLEX can check your email address and the email addresses of your contacts with the email addresses that you have provided to the service provider. or third-party websites.

If you are a User of a Client with more than one license, the Administrator of your account may have access to detailed information about the activity of your VLEX account, which includes registration information, connection to VLEX and details of your searches and documents consulted. If you provide personal information, you acknowledge that such data may be viewed by other members of your Organization.

VLEX and its affiliates may provide personal information to a governmental, judicial or security agency that requests such information in accordance with the law. VLEX will provide reasonable collaboration and information to respond to such request and, you are hereby informed in this regard.

Information collected or sent by VLEX may be stored and processed in the European Union, the United States or in any other country where VLEX facilities or its affiliates, subsidiaries or service providers are located. In this sense, or in order to share or disclose information as indicated in this article 4, VLEX reserves the right to transfer information outside the user’s country. By using the VLEX Services and VLEX websites or VLEX products, you expressly authorize such transfer of information outside of your country. The information collected within the European Economic Area (“EEA”) and Switzerland may, for example, be transmitted to, and stored by, companies of the VLEX group, its affiliates and the third parties identified above, in a country outside the EEA and Switzerland where your legal coverage may be lower in relation to your information. However, VLEX will only process your information as described in this Privacy Policy.

As VLEX continues to expand its commercial activity, VLEX will be able to buy or sell subsidiaries or business units. In transactions where VLEX or virtually all of VLEX’s assets were acquired by a third party, the personal information of VLEX users will generally be one of the commercial assets transferred. We reserve the right to include your personal information in any such transfer to a third party.

### **4\. WHAT ARE COOKIES AND GIFS AND HOW DOES VLEX USE THEM?**

Main points:  
By using the Service or VLEX websites, you consent to the use of cookies. You can choose to reject cookies at any time, either by changing the browser configuration (if your browser allows it), stopping use of the VLEX software or websites or using the corresponding cancellation functions. Please note that some features are only available through the use of cookies and if you choose not to accept them, these features may not be available.

### **4.1 What are cookies and GIFs?**  

### **4.1.1. cookies**

Cookies are small files that contain a series of characters (text) that are sent to your browser from the server of a website. The cookie may have a unique identifier but does not contain personally identifiable information, such as your name or email address. VLEX may use cookies when you visit its websites, use VLEX software or visit other websites where VLEX advertises. The VLEX software client browser or your Internet browser stores the cookie on the hard drive of your computer and the website can access it during your next visit. Other websites may also send cookies to your browser but it will not allow those websites to view the VLEX cookie information.

### **4.1.2. Gifs**

VLEX web pages and client interfaces can include transparent gifs, also known as web beacons and tracking pixels. A gif is a small graphic with a unique identifier, which is used to keep track of a user’s visits to the pages (but does not retain any type of information that identifies it). VLEX also uses transparent gifs in HTML-based emails to find out which email messages have been opened and answered. This allows us to evaluate the effectiveness of certain communications and our marketing campaigns.  

### **4.2 What kind of cookies does VLEX use?**  

VLEX uses session cookies, persistent cookies and shared local objects (Flash cookies).  
Session cookies are temporary cookies or unique identifiers associated with your browser for the duration of your visit to the VLEX websites or to the VLEX software client area. Once you close your browser, the identification of the session cookie will disappear and information about your visit will not be saved.

Persistent cookies remain in your browser even after you close it and your browser can use them in subsequent visits to the website.  
Shared local objects or “Flash cookies” are cookies written with Adobe Flash technology. These cookies are stored on your computer equipment like other cookies but can not be administered at the browser level in the same way.

###   
**4.3 How VLEX uses cookies**

VLEX uses its own cookies for a variety of purposes, including the following:  

  1. Recognize when you log in and understand how you came to our website so we can make sure you provide information and content relevant to the client
  2. Remember your chosen preferences, for example the language you choose to view our website
  3. Fight against fraud
  4. Block accounts based on service abuses
  5. Allow you access to your account and account services through the VLEX Service
  6. Provide internal and client analysis, and obtain metrics and indicators on our websites, such as the total number of visitors and page views
  7. Control the effectiveness and performance of our advertising and marketing campaigns and conduct research to help us improve our products and websites
  8. Take security measures, for example, disconnection after a certain time
  9. Providing VLEX ads that are commensurate with your interests when you visit other sites that show VLEX advertising

### **4.4 Third party cookies**

In addition to VLEX cookies, members and partners of VLEX advertising and analysis services can set cookies and access cookies on your computer, when you are using VLEX software or by visiting the VLEX website.  

### **4.4.1 Analysis**

VLEX uses partners for analysis, including Google Analytics, KISS Metrics and Mixpanel, in order to collect statistics and analysis information about how users use websites and VLEX Services. For example, these partners collect and aggregate data about page views and clicks on our sites, the search engines and keywords used to find our sites, the links that are accessed from them, information about errors and blockages of our clients and similar information.  

### **4.4.2 Advertising**

The VLEX and third-party advertising that appears on the VLEX Website, the VLEX Services and the third-party websites provided by Google, Inc. or other advertising service partners (“Advertising Services Partners”) is carefully selected.  
VLEX and its Advertising Services Partners may use non-personal information that you have provided in your VLEX profile or that someone else has provided tp VLEX to provide advertising that may be of most interest to you and to help us evaluate and improve performance of our advertising campaigns. VLEX and our Advertising Services Partners may use cookies or web beacons (gif) to collect this information.

### **4.4.3. Affiliates**

Sometimes VLEX can use third parties to promote VLEX services and compensate them for the income generated. To this end our affiliates can send cookies to your team to receive information (a) when you click on a link related to VLEX on the site of one of our affiliates or (b) when you make a purchase on the VLEX website, in order to pay a commission to the affiliate partner. If you revisit the VLEX site directly, our partner of the network of affiliated companies can recognize it and give back to the site of the affiliated collaborator who sent it to our site. These cookies are beyond the control of VLEX.

### **4.4.4. Other third-party content**

Sometimes, VLEX websites may include widgets or third-party embedded video content, such as YouTube. When you view this content or use the widget, you may be accepting cookies from these websites. These cookies are not within our control. For more information, you must contact the corresponding site.  

### **4.5 Your cookie options**

We do not recommend restricting or blocking cookies, as this may affect the operation of our Services and Websites. However, if you decide to do so, you can find complete information in, (Europe) or (United States). You can check [here](http://kb.vlex.com/en/knowledge-base/cookie-and-privacy-management/) how to change your privacy preferences and cookies in vLex.

### **5\. PERSONAL DATA IN THE CONTENTS OF VLEX**

Sometimes databases of legal information may incorporate names of persons or other personal data that are an intrinsic part of the legal or legal content and, which are also published by public or governmental sources accessible to the public, who originally published said documents. VLEX is committed to complying with the personal data regulations of each country or jurisdiction, therefore it eliminates this personal data at least in those cases where it is required by current regulations in the country where said document has been published. However, if you believe that, by mistake, you have personal data that was not deleted that should be deleted, or that a document cites your name or other personal information, and that this causes you a loss, we invite you to Contact the Department of Privacy and we will study your case with the utmost diligence attending, among other criteria, to the legislation of the country where you are.  

### **6\. USER PROFILE**

The user profile is the information you provided when registering, that appears in your VLEX account. It can include your user name, full name, address, landline and mobile numbers, country, language, legal specialization areas, and any other type of information you choose. You can access your user profile from the “Account” option in the VLEX Service to view, correct or complete information, remove information that is not required and to consult the privacy settings related to your profile information.

### **7\. LINKED SITES AND THIRD PARTY APPLICATIONS**

On VLEX websites, there may be links that will allow you to leave the VLEX site and access another website. The linked sites are not under the control of VLEX and have different privacy policies. The VLEX Privacy Policy only affects the personal information that is obtained from the websites, through your use of the VLEX software or the VLEX products, or through your relationship with VLEX. For this reason, VLEX urges the user to be careful when entering any type of personal information on the Internet. VLEX accepts no responsibility for such websites.  

### **8\. HOW DOES VLEX PROTECT ITS PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

VLEX must take the appropriate technical and organizational measures to protect the personal information and search information provided to it or that it has collected, with due compliance with the corresponding obligations and exceptions in accordance with current legislation. Only authorized employees of VLEX or its affiliates, subsidiaries or service providers that need access to such information in order to fulfill their work tasks may have access to the user’s personal information or traffic information.  

### 9\. **DELIVERY OF VLEX DOCUMENTS BY MAIL  
**

The VLEX Service allows documents to be sent by mail. If you want to use this service, a web page containing a form will be opened in which you can add one or more email addresses. The information entered in this form will only be used to automatically send an email message to said users. It will not incorporate them into their databases, nor use them for different purposes or assign them to third parties. By entering your email address, you confirm that the recipient has authorization for data to be provided. In the message we send to the recipient, VLEX will identify you as the person who sent the mail and may include your name, email address or phone number.

### **10\. CONTACT WITH THE USER**

VLEX may occasionally request information about your experiences, in order to use it to evaluate and improve quality. At no time will you be obligated to provide such information. All information that you voluntarily submit through the comments forms on the website or any survey in which you participate will be used to analyze that information and improve the VLEX Services, and other websites and products of VLEX.  
VLEX can contact you to send you messages about errors or service problems.  
VLEX, based on its legitimate interest, may use the provided telephones, emails, FAX and the VLEX Service itself to make promotional communications of Products and Services of VLEX, its affiliates and its commercial partners and to notify you of any related event with the use or payment of VLEX, the Services or VLEX websites. VLEX may also use e-mail, SMS or the VLEX Service to keep you up to date with news of VLEX Services or provide you with other information related to VLEX.

### **11\. HOW CAN YOU EXERCISE YOUR RIGHTS ON YOUR PERSONAL DATA?**

You have the right to access your personal information and to modify it when necessary. You can view or modify part of your information on the Internet by logging into your VLEX account page. Within a reasonable period and once your identity is verified, we will respond to your request to view, correct, complete or remove your personal information.  
VLEX will make all reasonable efforts to comply with requests for the removal of personal information, unless it is required to be retained by a legal requirement or for lawful commercial purposes.  
At any time you can exercise your rights of access, rectification, cancellation and opposition, and, where appropriate, the right of portability and limitation of processing, collected in the RGPD (EU) 216/679, to: C / Almogàvers 119 , 4th floor, 08018 Barcelona or by email to [dpo@vlex.com](mailto:dpo@vlex.com). For any concerns, you can contact the Spanish Agency for Data Protection www.agpd.es, to initiate the appropriate procedures to defend your rights.

### **12\. HOW LONG DOES VLEX SAVE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

VLEX will keep the user’s personal information as long as it is necessary to: (1) comply with any of the Objectives mentioned in this Privacy Policy, (2) comply with current legislation, regulatory requirements and pertinent orders of competent courts,or, in any case, (3) for a period never exceeding 10 years from the end of the contractual relationship with the user.

VLEX will take the appropriate technical and security measures to protect user information. By using VLEX Services, you are informed and agree that VLEX may store searches, documents consulted and interactions with the Services as described above.

### **13\. DOES VLEX CARRY OUT INTERNATIONAL DATA TRANSFERS?**

On occasion, we may use SaaS applications or host your data on servers outside the European Economic Area. In such a case, we always make sure that these suppliers are located in countries with an adequate level of protection and offer guarantees of compliance with European regulations on data protection, and in particular, the RGPD. For transfers to the USA, we will always work with suppliers that adhere to the Privacy Shield EU – USA.  

### **14\. CAN THIS PRIVACY POLICY BE MODIFIED?**

In some cases, VLEX will update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in our Services and customer feedback. When we post changes to the Privacy Policy we will update the “last revision” date at the bottom of the Privacy Policy. If there are important changes to this Privacy Policy or how we will use your personal information, we will notify you by posting a notice of such changes before implementation or by directly sending you a notice. You agree that the continuation of your use of VLEX Services after you have been notified constitutes your acceptance of the Privacy Policy. We recommend that you periodically review this Privacy Policy to learn how VLEX collects, uses and protects your information.  

### **15**. **HOW TO CONTACT VLEX?**

To communicate with VLEX in relation to the “VLEX” Brand Services, send your request for assistance to the customer support team.  
If you reside in the European Union: VLEX NETWORKS, SL – Almogàvers 119-123 – 08017 Barcelona (Spain). TLF. (+34) 93 272 26 85 or C / Edgar Neville, 6 – 28020 Madrid (Spain). TLF. (+34) 902 301 402  
If you reside outside the EU: VLEX LLC – 1200 Brickell – Ave – Suite 1950 – 33131 Miami, FL. email support@vlex.com or servicliente@vlex.com

### **16.** HOW TO CONTACT OUR DPO?

In virtue of the obligations derived from the RGPD, VLEX has appointed a Data Protection Officer with whom it will be able to contact through the channels enabled for such purposes:  
e-mail: dpo@vlex.com  
Phone: 932 722 685.  
Address: C / Almogàvers 119,4th floor, 08018 Barcelona.

### **17\. CONTACT FORMS, INFORMATION REQUESTS, OR CHATBOX**

If you contact us through one of our contact forms, requests for information or chatbox, the purpose of processing your data will be to respond to your query in order to provide you with information of interest about the activity of VLEX and inform you about our products and services We can do so by contacting you electronically or by telephone.

We can also contact you to inform you about news, offers or promotions of VLEX through these same routes (telephone and electronic) based on our general corporate interest.

We will not use your data for other purposes or assign them to third parties in any case.

The data related to your query or information request will be kept for the time necessary to respond to your query, and to meet our legal obligations. This period, in no circumstances, will exceed 5 years since your consultation.

### **II PERSONAL DATA INCLUDED IN THE VLEX DATABASES**

VLEX markets databases of legal information that contain:  
a) Legislation and Official Journals  
b) Jurisprudence  
c) Contracts  
d) Books and Legal Journals  
At times, these databases may incorporate names of persons or other personal data that are an intrinsic part of the legal or legal content, and which are also published by public or governmental sources accessible to the public, which originally published said documents. VLEX is committed to complying with the personal data regulations of each country or jurisdiction, therefore it eliminates this personal data at least in those cases where it is required by current regulations in the country where said document has been published. However, if you believe that, by mistake, you have personal data that has not been deleted that should be deleted, or that a document cites your name or other personal information, which causes you a loss, we invite you to Contact the Department of Privacy and we will study your case with the utmost diligence attending, among other criteria, to the legislation of the country where you are.  
Contact information:  
VLEX.COM (Privacy Department)  
Almogàvers 119-123, 3rd floor, 08018 Barcelona, Spain.  
E-mail: dpo@vlex.com  
Telephone: (+34) 932 722 685. Fax: (+34) 933 807 710

You can also fill out this form below:

Form:

**Affected Person**  
---  
Full name: |   
E-mail: |   
Telephone number: |   
Country of residence: |   
Person making the request: (complete only if different from the person concerned)  
Full name: |   
E-mail: |   
Telephone number: |   
URL of the document or documents implicated. For example: “http://libros-revistas-derecho.vlex.es/vid/comentario-sentencia-segovia-seccion-382483501”  
Search words used in google or other search engines that led you to retrieve the above documents:  
Request Motive
